Alissa Troiano

Full-Stack Software Developer

alissatroiano@alissatroiano.com | 914-562-0119 | github.com/alissatroiano | linkedin.com/in/alissatroiano/ | alissatroiano.com

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

A results-driven Software Developer with experience participating in the full software development life-cycle, from planning to deployment. Willing to learn new technologies, work long hours and do whatever it takes to succeed. To see my projects and repositories, please review my GitHub (https://github.com/alissatroiano)

SKILLS

Languages: Python, SQL, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3 Frameworks: Django, Flask, React, MVC, Bootstrap, jQuery

Database: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL, SQLite3

Server-Side: HTTP & REST API methods, NodeJS

Command Line Tools: Git, VSCode, Bash, Z Shell, PyPi, NPM

Deployment: AWS, Google Cloud, Heroku

EDUCATION

01/2020 - 08/2021 | Diploma in Full Stack Software Development | Code Institute - Dublin, Ireland 01/2009 - 05/2012 | BS, Advertising Marketing & Communications | Fashion Institute of Technology - NY, NY | GPA 3.8

HONORS & AWARDS

07/16/2022 1st Place Code Institute Emoji Day Hackathon Emojourney Travel Guide (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript)
06/20/2022 1st Place Code Institute Pride Hackathon Inklusion LGBTQIA+ Art Gallery (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript)
04/22/2022 1st Place Code Institute Earth Day Hackathon Electrillo EV/Fuel Savings Tool (JavaScript, HTML, CSS, JSON)
02/28/2022 1st Place Code Institute Valentine's Day Hackathon Smitten Word game (JavaScript, HTML, CSS, JSON)
11/28/2020 Merit Award for Code Institute Milestone 2 Project Game of Facts Trivia game (JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS)
07/10/2020 Distinction Award for Code Institute Milestone 1 Project Infinity Frontend website (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap)

EXPERIENCE

07/2019 - Present | Nanny (Pelham, NY) | Care for and teach basic computing principles to 9-year-old

- Entrusted with after-school pickup, homework help, and misc. tasks each day
- Use technical knowledge to teach basic computing principles and logistics to apprentice

01/2019 - 08/2021 | Student at Code Institute (Virtual) | Acquired software development knowledge and skillset

- Learned agile software development principles and best practices
- Harnessed new tools & technologies to create a portfolio of web applications

06/2018 - 07/2019 | Freelance Graphic Designer (Virtual) | Used graphic design skills to sell freelance services

- Designed wedding seating charts, welcome signs, invitations, and other custom graphics for clients
- Used semantic web knowledge to increase views and maximize online presence

ACTIVITIES

10/2021 - Present | Hack Team Leader at Code Institute Hackathons | Use agile tools to lead teams in five-day coding challenges.

- Oversee software development team in planning, developing & executing new projects each month
- Use Git to manage contributions, train team members in version control, and introduce agile development practices

06/2021 - 06/2022 | Tester at GitHub Copilot Technical Preview | Test prediction patterns of AI during its' beta phase

- Document AI prediction patterns and behavior during local development
- Report bugs and feedback to GitHub's technical preview community